这是我们离开时的浓缩课程第十讲
this is now the tenth lecture of the
condensed matter course when we left off
上一次我们谈论三维的晶格时，我们已经介绍了
last time we were talking about lattices
in three dimensions we've covered the
简单的立方晶格或原始立方晶格，我们已经移至主体
simple cubic lattice or primitive cubic
lattice and we've moved on to the body
居中居中立方居中立方晶格或BCC或立方-
centered body centered cubic body
centered cubic lattice or BCC or cubic -
我和我们有一张图片，显示了以身体为中心的常规晶胞
I and we have a picture of that the
conventional unit cell the body centered
立方晶格看起来像这样，在所有
cubic lattice looks something like this
there's a 1-point shared among all the
八个角，八个八分之一，然后在中心
eight corners one eighth times eight of
them and then one in the center of the
常规单元在常规单元中产生两个晶格点
conventional unit cell making two
lattice points in the conventional unit
单元格，您可以从上方查看事物，在此平面图方案中，
cell you can look at the thing from
above and in this plan view scheme where
您可以适当地标记所有高度，因此这里
you label all of the heights
appropriately so this point here
在此对应于此点，并说未标记的点在高度0处，
corresponds to this point here and says
unlabeled points are at height zero and
因此，如果您实际放置原子，则此点的高度为零，高度为a
a so this point is at height zero and
height a now if you actually put atoms
在以身体为中心的立方晶格的晶格点上，您注意到
at the lattice points of the body
centered cubic lattice you notice that
您非常有效地包装了球体，填补了您的空缺
you packed the spheres fairly
efficiently you filled the hole that you
如果只是一个简单的立方晶格就会有，因此
would have had if it was just a simple
cubic lattice and because of that this
是原子许多元素的更普遍的安排锂钠
is a much more common arrangement for
atoms lots of elements sodium lithium
铁钾都具有体心立方晶格构型
iron potassium all take body centered
cubic lattice configurations it's
从这张照片可以明显看出，协调数
obvious from this picture that the
coordination number the number of
如果您考虑它中心的球体，则最近的邻居是8
nearest neighbors is eight if you think
about the sphere in the center it has
显然，顶部有四个邻居，底部有四个邻居，总共
obviously four neighbors on top and four
neighbors on bottom making a total
协调数8对您来说可能并不明显
coordination number of 8 it may not be
obvious to you that every point in this
晶格彼此相等，这是我们对a的定义之一
lattice is equivalent to each other
that's one of our definitions of a
每个晶格点都应具有相同的环境，所以我们将
lattice that every lattice point should
have the same environment but so we'll
很好地看这张照片，这显然是这个领域
look at this picture here well most is
this this sphere here is obviously in
黄色轮廓立方体的中心，但是如果我们取其中之一的黄色
the center of the yellow outline cube
but if we take one of the yellow of one
黄色轮廓立方体的四角之一，它也位于
of the corners of the yellow outline
cube like that one it is also in the
另一个立方体的中心，所以每个球体都认为它们在一个立方体内
center of another cube so each sphere
thinks that they are inside a cube so
每个球体的每个点都是等价的，可能不是
every sphere every point of the lattice
is equivalent that may not be a
有说服力的论点足以说服您BCC实际上是
sufficiently convincing argument to
convince you that the BCC is actually a
所以我们应该做的是写下我的晶格向量
lattice so what we should do is we
should write down the lattice vectors my
检查员将使用以下内容编写为uvwxa晶格常数a
inspectors which will write as u v w x a
lattice constant a with the following
可能性可能性1要么与可能性要么呆在一起1全部
possibilities possibility 1 either stay
with either possibility 1 all business
声音消失了，你能说出某事消失了吗
out and the sound is falling out
can you name something something's gone
错误可以召唤回去修理，如果我使用其他麦克风或
wrong can can summon back there fixing
it should I use the other microphone or
我应该看看好吗，也许我们会杀死声音，然后
should I just see good yeah man maybe
maybe we kill the sound and then and
我只想大声一点，那就是有人可以回到那里更好，是的，所以我不是说
I'll just yell is that better
can someone back there yeah so no I mean
应该有一个人回到那里，那里没有人回到我那里
there should be someone back there who's
there's not someone back there I have no
想法就是这个关键，只要继续前进，看看我们是否可以忍受它
idea it's just this key just keep going
and see if we can suffer through it for
一会儿有人会打赌那个人的赌注又回来了
a while someone would that's the
person's bet is back there is fixing it
好吧，希望这将得到解决，如果仍然无法解决，请阻止我
ok so hopefully this will get fixed stop
me if it doesn't okay anyway you can
阅读如果您听不到声音，您仍然可以阅读，所以我们要写
read you can still read if you can't
hear so we're gonna we're gonna write
向下将晶格矢量作为UV W乘以a，并包含所有UV W整数和
down the lattice vectors as UV W times a
with either all of the UV W integers and
如果您以常规方式查看此整数，则对应的很好
the integer case corresponds to well if
you look in this in the conventional
晶胞是晶胞的角，因此该晶胞具有坐标1 0 0
unit cell it's the corners of the unit
cell so this one has coordinate 1 0 0
这个有1 1 0等等，以此类推，另一个可能是UV和W uv
this one has 1 1 0 and so forth and so
on the other possibility is UV and W u v
w所有半个奇数整数1/2个奇数整数和一半的奇数我的意思是一半
w all half odd integers 1/2 odd integers
integers and by half odd I mean one half
三个一半五个一半，依此类推，这对应于最平坦的
three half five halves and so forth and
that corresponds to the the the flattest
点在立方体的中心，例如，此点将具有
points in the center of the cube for
example this point here would have
协调一半一半一半一半，所以这一半将是一半一半
coordinates one half one half one half
so this one would be one half one half
一半，这个一半是一半，一半是一半，依此类推，
one half this one would be one half
three halves one half and so forth and
所以现在我们应该检查一下以使我们的
so on now
we should check to make one of our
或我们应该能够添加的晶格矢量的定义
definitions of lattice vectors of a
lattice or that we should be able to add
任何两个晶格矢量在一起，并获得另一个晶格矢量，它应该是
any two lattice vectors together and get
another lattice vector it should be a
加法下的封闭集，因此我们应该检查是否将整数添加到
closed set under addition so we should
check well if we add integers to
整数，我们回到整数，所以如果我们添加具有
integers we get back to integers so
that's good if we add integers that have
奇整数我们将整数取一半，所以如果再加上一半就很好
odd integers we get back half on
integers so that's good if we add half
在整数上，在一半上，我们返回整数，所以它可以工作
on integers and half on integers we get
back integers so it's gonna work either
方式彼此添加您会得到一些回馈
way add any of these to each other
you'll get back something it's either
这样的，这样就很好，使它成为格子
this kind of this kind so that's that's
good so that makes this a lattice so
让我们看看这里我们去那里我们去写下原始图很有用
let's see here we go there we go it's
it's useful to write down the primitive
这个晶格的晶格因子tlvs
lattice factors tlvs
for this lattice which we can take to be
一零零乘以一零一零乘以一，然后再二分之一
one zero zero times a zero one zero
times a and then one half one half one
半数，所以让我们在这里看到这个图，所以它是一个零零
half times a so let's see that on this
on this plot here so it's one zero zero
乘以一零一零乘以a和二分之一乘以a的一半
times a zero one zero times a and one
half one half one half times a and to
让自己相信这些东西是原始的晶格向量，我们要做的就是
convince yourself that these things are
primitive lattice vectors all we have to
要做的就是说服自己，您可以通过以下方式到达晶格的任何点
do is convince ourselves that you can
get to any point of the lattice by
将它们以整数组合加在一起，例如，如果我想
adding these together in integer
combinations so for example if I wanted
为了达到这一点，我会把这个家伙一两次，然后减去
to get to this point here I would take
this guy twice one two and then subtract
这个，那将带我从这里到这里，我会到达这个格子
this one and that would take me from
here to here and I'd get to this lattice
点，您可以通过将这些内容加在一起
point and you can sort of work out that
that by adding these together and all
最终可以到达每个晶格点的整数组合
integer combinations you can get
eventually to every every lattice point
到目前为止，一切都很好，现在没有警告，这是一个
good so far so good
all right now no warning and it's it's a
警告世界上每个人都应该采取的行动不要犯以下错误
warning that that everyone in the world
should take do not make the mistake of
称氯化铯为体心立方晶格，晶格规则为
calling caesium chloride a body-centered
cubic lattice the rule of a lattice is
每个晶格点应该看起来相同，所以有
that every lattice point should look
identical so there is
这是身体中间的一个点，但与另一个不同
a point in the middle of the body here
but it's not identical to the other
点，所以它不是以人体为中心的立方晶格，而是具有
point so it's not a body centered cubic
lattice it's a simple cubic lattice with
一个基数，并且基数必须等于0 0 0处的等价原子1
a basis and the basis has to in
equivalent atoms one at 0 0 0 which is
铯和另一个在1/2 1/2和1/2这是氯，有一个
cesium and the other is at 1/2 1/2 and
1/2 which is chlorine there's a
差异，所以它不是以身体为中心的立方晶格，您会发现
difference so it's not body centered
cubic lattice you will find books that
犯这个错误，这超出了名义艾希尔的不同，
make this mistake this goes beyond
difference in nominal Eicher it's just
错误，称其为体心立方晶格纯铯是不正确的
wrong it is incorrect to call it body
centered cubic lattice cesium pure
铯，这里所有点上都有一个铯原子，甚至是
cesium where there is a cesium atom at
all the points here even the one in the
中心是一个以身体为中心的立方晶格，但是欢迎您称它为中心
center that is a body centered cubic
lattice but you're welcome to call it
您也可以称其为“体心立方”
you're also allowed to call it body
centered cubic is the same thing as
具有基础的简单三次方，其中基础是我们所讨论的基础
simple cubic with a basis with basis
where the basis that we're talking about
这里包括一个0 0 0点和一个1/2 1/2 1/2点，它们是
here includes a point at 0 0 0 and a
point at 1/2 1/2 1/2 those are
等价的陈述，我想这个陈述的简单点是
equivalent statements I suppose that the
simpler of this statements is to say
这是一个以身体为中心的立方晶格，但您可以编写一个以身体为中心的立方晶格
it's a body centered cubic lattice but
you can write a body centered cubic
晶格只是说它是简单的三次方，其基础包括一个晶格点
lattice is just saying it's simple cubic
with a basis including one lattice point
在一格点处0 0 0处1/2 1/2 1/2很好到目前为止很好现在
at 0 0 0 in one lattice point at 1/2 1/2
1/2 good so far so good all right now
您可能想知道为什么我们使用常规方法会遭受痛苦
you might wonder why is it we're
suffering through using a conventional
拥有一个以上单位的晶胞，其中有两个晶格点，而不是
unit cell that has one more you one that
has two lattice points in it instead of
使用基本单元，它只有一个晶格点，不是
using a primitive unit cell it only has
one lattice point in it wouldn't that be
比较容易，这是有一个原因，我们不使用基本单元
easier well there's a reason we don't
use a primitive a primitive unit cell
因为原始的晶胞看起来有点丑陋，所以这是个大神经
because the primitive unit cell is kind
of ugly looking so this is the big nur
为BCC晶格定位原始单位单元，它被截断了
sites primitive unit cell for the BCC
lattice and it's it's a truncated
八面体我认为它有14个面，您可以看到这里发生了什么
octahedron I think it has 14 sides and
you can kind of see what's going on here
在这个立方体的中心，有一个晶格点，
this is in the center of this cube
there's one of the lattice points and
这是八个邻居，您可以看到所有e8邻居和
here are the eight neighbors which you
can see all e8 neighbors and the
六边形面是这两个面之间的垂直平分平面
hexagonal faces are the perpendicularly
bisecting planes between this the
立方体中心的晶格点和立方体角的晶格点
lattice point in the center of the cube
and the lattice point in the corner of
立方体的方形面是两边之间的垂直平分线
the cube the square faces are the
perpendicularly bisect ins between the
立方体中心的晶格点和邻居的晶格点
lattice point in the center of the cube
and the lattice point in the neighbor
使立方体居中，因此，如果您越过一个立方体
centering cube so if you go over one
cube
然后在那个立方体的中心有一个晶格点
and you have a lattice point in the
center of that cube and you make a
垂直平分线平面，为您提供这些正方形的面，记住了方式
perpendicular bisector plane that gives
you these square faces remember the way
您通过垂直平分线来构造单元，因此您
you construct the figner sight cells by
making perpendicular bisectors so you
知道太空中最接近该点的一个点
know that everything in space that's
closest to the one lattice point in the
中心在该对象的内部，所以它是一个难看的形状的对象，这就是为什么
center is on the inside of that object
so it's an ugly shaped object that's why
我们不将原始单位单元用于BCC晶格，但是如果您采用这些
we don't use primitive unit cells for
the BCC lattice but if you do take these
这些截断的八面体的丑陋形状的物体
ugly shaped objects these truncated
octahedron
他们将很好地堆叠在一起，并铺满所有空间
they will stack together very nicely and
tile all the space filling all space
因为他们应该没问题，所以还有另一种类型的晶格
appropriately as they're supposed to
okay there's one more type of lattice
我们需要讨论哪个是面心立方晶格面
that we need to discuss which is the
face centered cubic lattice face
居中居中立方或FCC或立方-f您可能已经注意到我写了一个
centered centered cubic or FCC or cubic
- f you may have noticed that I wrote a
以美国方式而不是英国方式为中心，我这样做的原因是
centered the American way not the
British Way and the reason I do this is
因为我做了另一种方式，我的大脑会爆炸，就是你知道你得到了
because I did the other way my brain
would explode it's just you know you get
曾经以一种方式做某件事，而你只是不能改变任何一种方式都是正确的
used to doing something one way and you
just can't change either way is correct
因此，根据您所在的海洋一侧，让我们看看脸
so depending on the side of the ocean
you're on so let's see what the face
居中的立方晶格看起来像，所以您从一个简单的立方晶格开始
centered cubic lattice looks like so you
start with a the simple cubic lattice
常规单位单元角落的点，然后添加
the points in the corner of the
conventional unit cell and then you add
像这样在每个人的脸中央居中
one point in the centre of every face
like this one in the center this place
是这张脸的中心之一，这张脸的中心之一，依此类推
is one of the center this face is one of
the center this face and so forth
里面有多少个晶格点
how many lattice points are there in the
所以是的，我将不得不加倍努力，是的，其中有四个要点
so yeah I'm gonna have to make these
harder yes there are four points in the
传统上你自己会看到四个点在哪里，八个
conventional yourself there's to see
where the four points are there's eight
每个角落都有八分之一，所以传统的里面有1/8
corners each of which counts one eight
so there's 1/8 inside the conventional
您卖出然后有六个空格，脸中心的点是
you sell then there are six spaces and
the point in the center of the face is
一半在晶胞内，一半在晶胞外，所以是6倍
half inside the unit cell and half
outside the unit cell so it's 6 times
1/2等于常规晶胞内的四个晶格点，您也可以
1/2 equals four lattice points within
the conventional unit cell you can also
使用此平面图方案绘制单元格的惯例
draw the convention of the cell with
this this plan view scheme which you
知道所以这里是角落里的要害，正如它所说的未贴标签
know so here are the points in the
corners and it as it says unlabeled
点是高度为0的点，因此此点对应于此点
points are height 0 on a so this point
here corresponds to this point here
在a的高度为0的位置上，您可以看到该点的高度
which is at height 0 on a you can see
the points on this on the halfway up the
高度超过2的脸，这就是这一点
faces at height labeled a over 2 so
that's this point this point this point
在这一点上，这是这个，这个，这个，然后一个，然后一个
on this point that's this one this one
this one and this one and then the one
在这中心的这个高度也是0
in the center here is also at height 0
on a this one and this one here ok now
如果您想象在FCC晶格中将原子或球体排列在一起
if you imagine arranging atoms together
or spheres together in the FCC lattice
配置实际上是您可以打包的最有效方法
configuration it is actually the most
efficient way that you can possibly pack
球在一起，因此，如果您有一束网球，您会尝试粘住
spheres together so if you have a bunch
of tennis balls you're trying to stick
把它们装进一个盒子里，把那些网球的最高密度的包装放进去
them into a box the highest density
packing of those tennis balls into the
盒子是FCC格子，还有其他包装，密度也相当
box is an FCC lattice there are other
packings which are equivalently dense
但是您永远不会比FCC包装做得更好，我们不会研究其他包装
but you're never going to do better than
the FCC packing we don't study the other
填料的类型，因为它们没有正交轴，但它们是
types of packings because they don't
have orthogonal axes but they're
实际上等同于FCC，这说明您无法获得更密集的包装
equivalent to FCC in fact this statement
that you can't get a more dense packing
比FCC的原子数由开普勒（Kepler）在1611年推测
of atoms than FCC was conjectured by
Kepler in 1611
它只是在1998年被证明的，所以它是一个长期存在的定理，但是
and it was only proven in 1998 so it's a
very long standing standing theorem but
事实证明，你不能做得更好，不能打包
it turns out to be true
you can't do any better you can't pack
如果有担心，可以将更多的东西放到狭小的空间中，然后使用FCC晶格
more things into a small space if
there's fears then using FCC lattice
因为如果你考虑原子，那么你会在一个狭小的空间里放很多长矛
because you get so many Spears in a
small space if you think about atoms
试图吸引对方，这是很普遍的，这是非常有吸引力的
trying to attract each other it's a very
common it's a very appealing a
原子的组态，因此许多元素采用FCC组态
configuration for atoms and so many
elements take FCC configurations
铜，银，金，钙，许多其他都可以通过FCC进行，所以既然有四个
copper silver gold calcium many others
are FCC okay so since there are four
每个单位晶格的原子，我们应该能够在输入4时查看FCC晶格
atoms per unit cell we should be able to
view the FCC lattice as 4 enter
互穿简单的立方晶格，所以让我们看看是否可以看到这是
interpenetrating simple cubic lattices
so let's see if we can see that this is
FCC球体晶格，这是我标出的简单立方
an FCC lattice of spheres and this is
the red I have marked out a simple cubic
格子这是一个简单的立方体，很难看，但是您可以
lattice this is a simple cube it's a
little hard to see but then you can
如果您仔细看的话，请选择其他三个
actually pick out if you look very
carefully there are three other
相互渗透的简单立方晶格，在这里和尽管
interpenetrating simple cubic lattices
which are mixed in here and although it
每个球体的环境可能并不完全清楚
may not be completely obvious that the
environment of every single sphere is
现在与其他领域的环境相同，因为那不是
identical to the environment of every
other sphere now since that's not
完全显而易见，我们应该练习一下写下
completely obvious we should do the
exercise of actually writing down the
FCC晶格的晶格矢量我声称它们采用
lattice vectors lattice vectors for the
FCC lattice and I claim they take the
再次形成UV w UV W乘以a，其中一个UV W都为整数
form again UV w UV W times a where
either one UV W all integer and again
这将对应于备份另一个
that would correspond backing up one
more that would correspond to the the
将所有整数都指向角，所以这个1是1 0 0这是1 1 0并且
points in the corners all integers so
this one is is 1 0 0 this is 1 1 0 and
等等，还有其他可能性，所以紫外线W
so forth and so on
the other possibility so UV W we're
要么可能性1都是整数，要么其中两个都是半奇数
either either possibility 1 they're all
integers or to two of them are half odd
整数和一个整数
integer and one integer
好吧，我们将证明它确实有效，但在继续之前
okay so we're gonna show that this
actually works but before going on so
再来一个巧克力，什么是协调
for the one one more chocolate
what is the coordination of the
协调数12让我们实际上在此图上看到的是
coordination numbers 12 let's actually
see on this on this on this plot y it is
协调号码是12我要停止问问题
the coordination number is is 12 I'm
gonna stop asking questions I'm gonna
这样运行巧克力，我将不得不问更难的问题
run that chocolate this way I'm gonna
have to ask harder questions okay
因此，如果您看到协调编号12，那么我们将这个领域
so if you see the coordination numbers
12 let's take this sphere here the one
它被切成两半，在同一高度有四个邻居一二三四
that's cut in half it has four neighbors
one two three four at the same height it
有四个邻居，高度略低一些，您可以看到其中两个
has four neighbors at a slightly lower
height here you can see two of them that
也触摸它，然后如果您走到更高的高度，
are touching it also and then if you
went to a slightly higher height the
距离这些下降的距离相同，您将再有四个距离，因此
same distance up that these are down you
would have four more so it's forth the
高度略低而略高的相同高度
same height for slightly lower and for
slightly higher which may not look all
令人信服，但我们可以使用此规则进行显示，因此该规则可以使
that convincing but we can show it using
this rule so this rule would give that
免费给我们的原因，我们知道这是因为
to us for free
the reason we would know this is because
如果您看的很好，首先让我们来
if you if you look at this point here
well first of all let's let's take a
看看这个项目到这里，他们两个都有奇数整数之一
look at this this item to here the two
of them have odd integer one of them
整数对应于什么，对应于
integer what does that correspond to
that corresponds to someone in the
例如脸部中间，这个家伙他已经回来了一半多
middle of the face for example this guy
here he's over one-half he's back
二分之一，但他的身高和整数身高，而这个家伙在这里，他已经结束了
one-half but he's up and integer height
whereas this guy over here he's over
他的一半上升了一半，但他的身高是整数，恰好是他的深度
one-half he's up one half but his height
is an integer it happens to be his depth
是一个整数，这个是1/2以上1/2的整数，他是整数，所以如果
is an integer this one here is over 1/2
up 1/2 and he's an integer back so if
它在脸上有两个一半的整数，如果有一个，则有一个整数
it's on a face it has two half out
integers and one integer if it's on a
角都是全整数，现在我们可以检查我们可以再次检查这里
corner it's all integers now we can
check we can check here that again we
应该具有以下规则：如果您将这些集合中的任何两项添加到彼此
should have the rule that if you add any
two things from these sets to each other
您应该从这些集合之一中获取一些东西，例如
you should get back something from this
from one of these sets so for example if
您添加引入两个整数，如果您将整数添加到
you add introduce two integers you get
back integers if you add integers to
半个奇数整数和一个整数，您会得到回报，您知道以下事实：
half odd integers and one integer you'll
get back you know the fact that you're
向某物添加整数不会改变它是否是一半整数
adding integers to something doesn't
change whether it's a half out integer
或整数，以便您再次获得第二组中的某项，但这不是
or an integer so you get back something
in the set two again but what's not
很明显，您需要做两件事，其中有两个半数整数和一个
obvious is you take two things which
have two half out integers and one
整数并将它们加在一起会得到什么，所以让我们尝试一下，如果有
integer and you add them together what
do you get so let's try so if you have
例如一半一半一半，然后将其添加到三个
for example one half
one half one and you add it to three
将一半减半，所以这两个都是其中一半我将整数之一
halves one half zero so both of these
are two of them half I'd integers one of
它们是整数，所以它们都在脸上，您会得到2逗号1逗号1
them integers so both of these would be
on the face you get 2 comma 1 comma 1
都是整数，这很好，但是我可以用不同的方式来做
which is all integers and that's good
but I could have done it differently you
本来可以有一个一半一个一半一个说一半的一半0 3一半
could have had one half one half one
added to say one half 0 3 halves for
例子，那么你得到的是1个逗号1个半逗号3个一半，还有两个
example then what do you get is 1 comma
1 half comma 3 halves and still two of
它们是1/2个奇数整数，其中一个是整数，所以如果加
them are 1/2 odd integers and one of
them is an integer so if you add
集合B的两件事在一起，您会从集合B中得到某事
together two things from set B you'll
get either something from set wasthat be
设置为您会从设置1或设置2中得到一些东西，因此它形成一个
set to you get either something from set
1 or something from set 2 so it forms a
假设我们知道这些是坐标，则加法下的闭集
closed set under addition now given that
we know that these are the coordinates
FCC格子中的向量的，让我们看看是否可以找出
of the of the vectors in the FCC lattice
let's see if we can figure out that that
协调编号12更容易一点，让我们从这一点开始
coordination number 12 a little more
easily so let's start with this point
这就是0 0 0的点，并寻找最接近0 0 0的东西最接近0
here that's the point 0 0 0 and look for
the closest things to 0 0 0 closest to 0
0 0好吧好吧这家伙看起来很近，他的警戒线是1/2 1/2逗号
0 0 okay well okay this guy here looks
pretty close his cordon is 1/2 1/2 comma
0，所以1/2 1/2逗号为0，如果它符合以下点之一的定义
0 so 1/2 1/2 comma 0 and if that fits
the definition of one of the points in
FCC晶格中的两个是一半整数，其中一个是整数，
the FCC lattice two of them half out
integers one of them integer and it's
非常接近无法接近，但我们可以
pretty close
can't get any closer but we could have
做这个正负，我们也可以做这个正负
made this plus or minus and we could
have made this plus or minus as well
正确的是，这些也都符合定义，我们可以将0放入
right that those all fit the definition
as well and we could have put the 0 in
三个地点中的任何一个，三种可能性，所以我们有四个
any of the three spots three
possibilities so we have four
这些加号或减号的可能性以及何处的三种可能性
possibilities of these plus or minus
signs and three possibilities of where
你把零，所以我们得到4乘以3等于12是协调数
you put the zero so we get 4 times 3
equals 12 is the coordination number
好吧好吧好吧，所以还值得写下一些原始的
okay good okay all right so it's worth
also writing down a set of primitive
FCC晶格的晶格矢量，因此FCC晶格的POV确实非常好
lattice vectors for the FCC lattice so
POVs for the FCC lattice a really good
例如，最接近的向量使它们很好剥皮
example are just the closest
vectors are make pretty good peel these
所以1/2 1/2 0倍1/2 0 1/2倍+ 0 1/2 1/2倍
so 1/2 1/2 0 times a 1/2 0 1/2 times a +
0 1/2 1/2 times a make pretty good
它们在那里是原始晶格向量，一次又一次地使自己相信它们
primitive lattice vectors there they are
and again to convince yourself that they
确实是原始晶格向量，我们要做的就是说服自己
really are primitive lattice vectors
what we have to do is convince ourselves
我们可以通过添加整数到达FCC晶格上的每个点
that we can get to every point on the
FCC lattice by adding integer
它们的组合，例如，如果我们想在这里达到这一点
combinations of them so for example if
we wanted to get to this point here
我们将不得不将其中每个添加1个，因此将这个添加为1个
we would have to add 1 of each of them
so this one this one plus this one would
带我们到这里，如果我们想到达这里，我们将不得不添加mmm
take us to here and if we wanted to get
to here we would have to add mmm well
我不确定是的，您如何到达其中两个，然后减去-1
I'm not sure yeah okay how do you get
there two of these and then minus 1 of
这些或其他内容，无论如何，您都可以使用它，它可以正常工作
these or something and anyway so you can
play around with it you it works you can
到达那里你如何到达这里嗯是的，这将是其中的两个
get there how do you how do you get here
um yeah so it would be two of these
会把你带到这里，那么你可能需要减去一-是其中之一，再加上
would get you here then you need maybe
minus one yeah - one of these then plus
其中之一是某种可以让您顺利到达的东西
one of these there's something that will
get you there okay anyway
好吧，因为FCC晶格具有FCC晶格，每个FCC晶格具有四个四个晶格点
alright so since the FCC lattice has FCC
lattice has four four lattice points per
常规单位单元，就像我们对BCC所做的那样，我们可以将其编写为简单
conventional unit cell just like we did
with the BCC we could write it as simple
立方简单立方乘以基数乘以基数，其中基数现在包括
cubic simple cubic times the basis times
a basis where the basis now includes
基数等于0 0 0的点等于1/2 1/2 0的点等于1/2 0
basis equals the point at 0 0 0 the
point at 1/2 1/2 0 the point at 1/2 0
1/2和0 1/2 1/2的点会给我四个晶格点
1/2 and the point at 0 1/2 1/2 that
would give me the four lattice points
每个单位单元格，如果我按照惯例翻译了这四个晶格点
per unit cell and if I translate those
four lattice points in my convention
他们会卖到每个格子点
they'd sell around to every lattice
point
所以晶格点在0 0 0，然后这些都从原始位置移开
so lattice points at 0 0 0 and then
these are all displace from the original
将重建整个面为中心的立方晶格的晶格点或
lattice point that will reconstruct the
entire face centered cubic lattice or
另一种思考方式是这些是四个的位移
another way of thinking about it is
these are the displacements of the four
互穿构成FCC晶格的简单立方晶格
interpenetrating simple cubic lattices
that make up the FCC lattice
与BCC晶格一样，有一个原因是我们不使用基本单位单元
as with the BCC lattice there's a reason
we don't use the primitive unit cell for
它使用传统的单元格而不是原始单元格，因为
it we use a conventional you cell not
the primitive unit cell because the
原始单元格在这里非常丑陋，它被截短到十进制
primitive unit cell is extremely ugly
here it is it's a truncated to deca
heatran它具有12个面，这12个面对应于12个最近的邻居
heatran it has 12 sides those 12 sides
correspond to the 12 nearest neighbors
所以我们在中心的是晶格点之一，然后我们有
so what we have in the center is one of
the lattice points and then we have the
12个最近的邻居，其中四个在同一位置略高于
12 nearest neighbors four of them
slightly above for them at the same
高度，并形成在略低于正十二面体的下面和面中
height and formed in slightly below and
the faces of the truncated dodecahedron
这是0和和之间的线段的垂直平分线
here are the perpendicular bisectors of
the segment between 0 and the and the
和最近的邻居好吧，这就是我们需要了解的FCC
and the nearest neighbors okay alright
that's all we need to know about the FCC
实际上这就是我们要使用的所有三个三维晶格
lattice in fact that's all the three
dimensional lattices we're going to
研究值得一提的是，总共有14种晶格
study it is worth knowing that there are
14 types of lattices in in all the ones
我们已经研究了立方本原体
we've studied are the cubic primitive
the cubic body-centered the cubic
以面子为中心，我们还讨论了四边形简单tr三角形和
face-centered we also talked about the
tetragonal simple trent trigonal and
简单的斜方晶，然后您在这里有一堆其他的
simple orthorhombic and then you have a
whole bunch of other ones here you may
注意那里有类似物，所以我们不需要知道身体的类似物
notice that there's there's analog so we
don't need to know analogues of the body
中心四角形体中心斜方面中心正交面
centered tetragonal body centred
orthorhombic face centred orthorhombic
依此类推，您可能会注意到没有以四角形为中心的人脸，其原因是
and so forth you may notice there's no
face centered tetragonal and the reason
因为这实际上是因为通过横向旋转晶格
for that is because in fact by turning
the lattice sideways it would be in one
以及其他类别的东西，所以无论如何您都将过度计算
of the other classes as well so you
would be over counting so anyway these
在brav a是谁之后，有时称为brav a晶格类型
are sometimes known as the brav a
lattice types after brav a who is the
第一人称正确写下来，所以我们赞扬
first person to write them down
correctly and so we give brav a credit
为此，这些是您可能拥有的唯一可能的晶格类型
for doing them so these are the only
possible lattice types you can have it's
一种深层的数学陈述，即三个周期中的任何周期结构
kind of a deep mathematical statement
that any periodic structure in three
您可以在三个维度中拥有的任何维度都是其中之一
dimensions anything you can have in
three dimensions is one of these
晶格乘以某个基础，所以如果您可以写下所有这些晶格，您
lattices times some basis so if you can
write down all these lattices and you
可以选择任何依据，无论您做任何事情多么复杂
can have any basis you choose no matter
how complicated you can make anything
任何周期性结构都是这些晶格之一乘以某些基数
any periodic structure is one of these
lattices times some bases the only ones
我们实际上必须要知道今年是三个立方，而这个和
we're actually gonna have to know this
year are the three cubics and this and
这三个简单的立方四方正交晶体很少需要
the three simple cubic tetragonal
orthorhombic very rarely do we need to
知道泰德·龙格定理，因为我很少参加考试
know Ted dragonlore theorem because I
only rarely come up on exams it's really
这三个在考试中名列前茅的好吗
these three across the top that actually
show up on exams okay
所以这是你可以放一个例子
so
this is an example of what you can put
当你有晶格和基础时，这是钠
together when you when you have a
lattice and a basis this is a sodium
氯化物结构非常典型的盐结构氯化钠非常离子
chloride structure a very typical salt
structure sodium chloride very ionic
钠释放电子氯会吸收电子，如果您看一下
sodium gives up the electron chlorine
takes the electron and if you look at it
仔细地您会看到钠正在形成FCC晶格，甚至
carefully you can see that sodium is
forming an FCC lattice this is even
标有立方的f，所以也许最容易在这张照片中看到这些
labeled cubic f so maybe it's easiest to
see in this picture these are all
同一格的描绘实际上都不是很好，但我们可能有
depictions of the same lattice none of
them are actually great but we may have
为此，您可以在这张图片中以FCC的形式看到此处的绿色球体。
to make do so here you can see the green
spheres here in this picture form an FCC
格子，所以它也位于脸部的角和中心
lattice so it's on the corners and in
the center of the faces as well but in
除了FCC晶格上的钠原子外，还有氯
addition to the sodium atoms which are
on the FCC lattice there are chlorine
原子也可以这样说：
atoms as well and you can describe the
position of the chlorine atoms by saying
每一个钠原子都有一个氯原子被二分之一取代
for every sodium atom there is a
chlorine atom displaced by one half one
钠原子的一半一半将使您处于
half one half from the sodium atom that
will that will get you the position of
所有的氯原子都是平面图蓝调是钠的
all the chlorine atoms here's a plan
view the Blues would be the sodium's and
氯，例如，如果我开始加钠，然后超过一半
the chlorines so for example if I
started a sodium and I go over a half
返回一半然后再向上延伸一半到下一层当我到达一个氯原子时
back a half and then up a half to the
next layer I get to a chlorine atom when
描述基础时，应始终描述基本单元的基础
you describe a basis you should always
describe the basis of the primitive unit
单元格，所以在这里我不告诉您这四个我不谈论的地方
cell so here I don't tell you where all
the four I don't talk about the
传统的晶胞，它只有四个钠和四个氯
conventional unit cell which would have
four sodium's and four chlorines I just
告诉你这是一个FCC格子，马上你知道
tell you there's it's an FCC lattice and
immediately you know that the
传统的静音单元将在其中和位置上具有四个晶格点
conventional muted cell will have four
lattice points in it and on the position
在零零零处有一个钠蓝色，然后从
of the lattice at zero zero zero there's
a sodium blue and then displace from
我把1/2 1/2 1/2加了氯，所以我只想向你描述一个
that by 1/2 1/2 1/2 I put a chlorine so
I only have to describe to you one
钠和一氯可以告诉你一切，一旦我告诉你这是
sodium and one chlorine to tell you
everything once I've told you it's a
简单立方，这是FCC晶格注意，我不是唯一的方式
simple cubic it's a it's a FCC lattice
notice also that it's not unique how I
描述了氯的位置相对于氯的位置
described the position of the chlorine
with respect to the position of the
钠我本可以告诉你，氯被置换为1/2 0 0
sodium I could have told you that the
chlorine was displaced 1/2 0 0 that
会给您相同的结构，或者我可能已经决定氯
would give you the equivalent structure
or I could have decided that chlorine
是我的零零零，钠是这个地方，它也会给
was my zero zero zero and sodium was
this place from it that would also give
您具有同等的结构，因此有多种不同的方式来描述
you an equivalent structure so there's
various different ways to describe the
相同的晶格这是我们运行的另一个结构
same the same lattice
here's another structure that we run
变成非常常见的金刚石结构碳
into very frequently the diamond
structure carbon it also is the
硅和锗的结构也基于FCC晶格，因此您可以
structure of silicon and germanium it is
also based on the FCC lattice so you can
举例来说，在上面，有一个家伙，有一个家伙，
see for example on the top face here
there's some guy there's one in all the
边角在一个角或中心，侧面是一个
corners and there's one or in the center
of the face the side face is one in all
角在脸中央有一个，依此类推，所以肯定
the corners there's one in the center of
the face and so forth so it's definitely
里面有FCC格子，但那并不能告诉您所有
has an FCC lattice in it but then that
that doesn't tell you where all the
碳的位置上还有其他碳，您可以描述
positions of the carbons are there
additional carbons and you can describe
碳的位置被四分之一取代
the position of the carbons by just as
being displaced by one quarter one
从每个晶格点开始四分之一四分之一，因此例如在平面图中
quarter one quarter from every lattice
point so for example in the plan view we
从0 0 0处的碳开始，然后我们将四分之一四分之一位移
start with this carbon at 0 0 0 and then
we displace by a quarter one quarter one
季度，我们也在该位置找到另一个碳，所以我再也没有
quarter and we find another carbon at
that position as well so again I don't
必须描述所有八个碳在常规碳中的位置
have to describe the position of all of
the eight carbons in the conventional
晶胞我只需要告诉你这是一个FCC晶格，并且它有一个
unit cell I only have to tell you that
it's an FCC lattice and and it has a
以两个原子为基础，一个在0 0 0，一个在1/4 1/4 1/4，这足以
basis of two atoms one at 0 0 0 and one
at 1/4 1/4 1/4 and that's sufficient to
好好描述一切，什么是格子，什么是
describe everything ok all right
what'swhat's the lattice what is the
晶格是什么晶格是什么晶格是有基础的晶格
lattice what is the lattice what it is a
lattice it's a lattice with a basis what
谁说的FCC格子类型好好好
what lattice type who said it FCC ok ok
good
哇，这是坐起来很方便的好处
Wow see this is advantage to sitting up
close you get more chocolate that way
顺便说一句，我尝试了一些
incidentally I switched from chocolate
types because I tried some of the
昨天的巧克力不好吃，所以希望有一点更好
chocolate yesterday wasn't all that good
so there hopefully this bit it's better
你们我是巧克力鉴赏家好吧，这是FCC，所以这是镓
you guys I'm chocolate connoisseur okay
so it's FCC it's it's so this is gallium
砷化物结构也称为锌混合结构
arsenide structure also known as the
zinc blende structure it's exactly the
与钻石结构相同，不同之处在于您已经获取了第二碳并
same as the diamond structure except
that you've taken the second carbon and
你把它变成了不同类型的原子，所以在这里让我向你展示
you turn it into a different type of
atom so here let me actually to show you
所以在我们FCC的F形中的黄色，所以您可以看到黄色原子
so the yellow at our F form at FCC so
you can see that the the yellow atoms
在脸部的角落和中心说，例如，这是一张脸
say in the corners and the centre of the
faces so for example here here's a face
中间有一个黄色然后蓝调被1/4 1/4 1/4取代
and there's a yellow in the center of it
then the Blues are displaced 1/4 1/4 1/4
从每个黄色原子开始，有些您知道它看起来有些令人困惑
from every yellow atom now some of the
you know it may look a little puzzling
看起来我们有比黄色原子更多的黄色原子，但我们没有
it looks like we have more yellow atoms
than we have blue atoms but we don't
因为有些黄色是我们晶胞内仅有的一半
because some of the yellow
our only half inside the unit cell the
FCC在晶胞内有四个晶格点，因此应该有
FCC there's four lattice points within
the unit cell and so there should be
四个黄色原子（如果算在内的话）包括八分之一
four yellow atoms if you count them
including you know it's half an eighth
如果它在拐角处，一半在侧面，您会算黄色
if it's on the corner and a half of its
on the side you'll count for yellow
原子，然后它们显然是完全位于单元内部的四个蓝色原子
atoms and then they're obviously four
blue atoms completely inside the unit
单元格还可以，还有一个评论，如果Mike Glaser，这是一个微妙的地方
cell as well okay um one more comment
this is a subtlety if Mike Glaser
碰巧是你的老师，他会很高兴我告诉你他是一个真正的
happens to be your tutor he'll be very
happy that I tell you this he's a real
清澈的晶体学家，他总是把我的脚扶在火上，迫使我
clear crystallographer and he always
holds my feet to the fire to force me to
以真实的方式讲事物，不讲任何谎言，所以我在这里讲
tell things the way they really are and
not tell any lies so here I'm gonna tell
你的微妙之处，不要告诉你任何谎言，所以假设我们有一个像
you the subtlety and not tell you any
lies so suppose we have a material like
这似乎是一个简单的三次系统，以三个为基础
this it appears to be a simple cubic
system with a basis of three there's one
在拐角处，然后在中心的两个地方，它们不正确
on the corners and then two somewhere in
the center they're not right in the
中心，所以它不是密件抄送，但中心有两个地方，有一个
center so it's not BCC but there's two
somewhere in the center and there's one
并由八个角落共享，所以我们可以说这是一个简单的立方体
and shared by all the eight corners so
we would say it's a simple cubic with a
如果我测量这个立方体的边缘，现在包括三个三三个原子
basis including three three three atoms
now if I measure the edges of this cube
我说它们都是相同的aa和a以及所有三个方向
and I say they're all the same a a and a
and all the three directions I would say
如果您很想说这是简单的立方晶体，但是
it's if you would be tempted to say it's
simple cubic crystal but a
晶体学家会说不是，而他们会说不是
crystallographers would say it's not and
the reason they would say it's not is
因为它没有简单立方物体的对称性
because it doesn't have the symmetry of
a simple cubic object a simple cubic
对象，您应该能够将其在所有六个方向上旋转，并且它看起来
object you should be able to turn it in
all six directions and it should look
不管您从哪个方向看，它都不会
the same whichever direction you look at
it from and this thing doesn't look the
如果从顶部看，就像从侧面看一样
same if you look at it from the top as
from as if you look at it from the side
结晶学家为什么知道这么重要
why is that important well the
crystallographer knows that if it
没有对称性，没有充分的理由将其高度设置为
doesn't have the symmetry there's no
good reason that its height should be
与其宽度相同，但不相同，在任何意义上都不相等
the same as its width they're not the
same they're not equivalent in any sense
因此高度不必与宽度相同，所以如果我告诉你
so the height doesn't have to be the
same as the width and so if I tell you
边缘的长度相同，他会说去测量
well the the the edges have the same
length he would say well go measure it
仔细一点，您会发现它们的长度不一样，所以
more carefully and you'll discover
they're not the same length so the
晶体学家知道边缘是否有很好的对称性原因
crystallographer knows if there's not a
good symmetry reason for the edge
长度是相同的，那么他们是不一样的，如果我是晶体学家
lengths to be the same then they're not
the same and a crystallographer if I
写下这个，晶体学家会回来找我，说不
wrote this down the crystallographer
would come back to me and say no they're
实际上长度不一样，您只是以为它们长度相同所以就去
actually not the same length you just
think they're the same length so go
再次测量，您会发现它们的长度不一样
measure it again and you'll discover
them they're not the same length it
如果没有很好的对称原因，这将是一个令人难以置信的巧合
would be an unbelievable coincidence if
there was not a good symmetry reason for
边缘的长度相同，最终导致人
the edges to be the same length and they
ended up people
长度一样可以让真正的晶体学家高兴
being the same length okay so that's to
make the real crystallographers happy
这就是我们今天要说的关于晶体结构的所有内容，所以很好
and that is all we have to say about
crystal structure for today okay good so
现在，我们已经了解了三个晶体结构所需的所有知识
we've now learned everything we need to
know about crystal structure in three
确定我们将要讨论的所有晶格的尺寸
dimensions all the lattices we're going
to have to discuss we know about
格子和花瓶，但归根结底，我们真的想形容
lattices and vases but at the end of the
day we really want to describe physical
这些晶体中的现象，而且通常不是我们感兴趣的现象
phenomena in these crystals and more
often than not what we're interested in
是某种波，无论是振动波还是声子
is waves of some sort whether the
vibrational waves or phonons whether
它们是电子波，无论是电磁波还是
they're electron waves whether
electromagnetic waves and the world of
方式是互惠空间的世界，所以我们必须备份并了解一些
ways is the world of reciprocal space so
we have to back up and understand some
当我们拥有复杂的晶体时，关于互易空间的事情，让我们
things about reciprocal space when we
have complicated crystals so let's
提醒自己一些我们在一个互惠空间中学到的东西
remind ourselves some things we learned
about this reciprocal space in one
一维很好，我们有一个形式为R sub的直接晶格
dimension well in one dimension we had a
direct lattice lattice of the form R sub
N等于N的乘积，并且整数a是原始晶格矢量p lv
N equals a times N and was the integer a
was the primitive lattice vector p lv
然后从直接空间我们得到倒数空间倒数格
and then from direct space we have the
reciprocal space reciprocal lattice
我们可以这样写：GM乘以M等于2 pi现在这里a的2 PI是
which we can write as G M equals 2 pi
over a times M now here 2 PI over a is
倒数空间中的本征格向量
the primitive lattice vector in
reciprocal space primitive lattice
现在倒数晶格的向量为什么为什么我们选择这个作为
vector for the reciprocal lattice now
why was it that we chose this to be the
倒数晶格很好，我们选择它是因为如果您取K 2 K加任何
reciprocal lattice well we chose it
because if you take K 2 K plus any
倒数晶格中的元素GM我们以相同的方式得到相同的结果
element GM in the reciprocal lattice we
get back the same way gets same way why
那好吧，让我们仔细地将e移到IK点RK点R上，
is that well let's do carefully e to the
I K dot R K dot R gets shifted to e to
IK加G m点RN，等于e等于IK点R ne
the I K plus G m dot RN and that
becomes equals e to the I K dot R n e to
i GM RN，这是一个因素，因为这是一个，因为
the i GM RN and this factor here is just
one because it's this is one because it
e到I到PI的时间是M乘以n的整数倍，所以我们要
is e to the I to PI over a times M times
a times n that's just one so we're going
将其概括为另外两个维度
to generalize that in two more
dimensions in any dimension in any
我们定义的维以找到倒数晶格定义
dimension we define to find the
reciprocal lattice define resupply
tiss-you SIPP Flat oh yeah points as points GG vector that that e
tiss-you SIPP flat oh yeah
points as points G G vector such that e
到i g-- m点RN o kg，我们不要在其上加上索引，但g RN等于1
to the i g-- m dot RN o kg let's not put
an index on it yet g RN equals 1 for all
因为所有人都在直接晶格中
for all are and in direct lattice
间接晶格，所以这是我们对等晶格的一般定义
indirect lattice so this is our general
definition of the reciprocal lattice
倒数晶格中的向量G现在这是一个很好的定义
vectors G in the reciprocal lattice now
this is a nice definition it's a very
有用的定义，但我没有以任何方式向您证明此定义
useful definition but I have not in any
way proven to you that this definition
定义了我声称的晶格，但定义了晶格，但我没有显示
defines the lattice that I've claimed it
defines the lattice but I haven't shown
您定义一个晶格并证明倒数空间中的点集G
you it defines a lattice and the proof
the set of points G in reciprocal space
对于直接晶格中的所有RN，满足此等式的方程等于1
that satisfy this equation equals 1 for
all RN in the direct lattice the proof
定义互易空间中的晶格有点微妙，
that that defines a lattice in
reciprocal space is a little subtle and
有点棘手，所以我们将通过它来看看是否可以做到
a little tricky so we're going to go
through it let's see if we can make it
说服它是真的，所以首先我们将采用直接晶格
convincing that it's true so first of
all we'll take the direct lattice
我们必须定义直接晶格矢量的因素直接晶格矢量
接下来，我们将根据原始晶格因子来写它们，因此R等于n1
next we'll write them in terms of the
primitive lattice factors so R equals n1
a 1加n 2 a 2加n 3 a 3其中原始晶格因子的A
a 1 plus n 2 a 2 plus n 3 a 3 where the
A's of the primitive lattice factors
我们的PL V的A是PL，这些是原始晶格向量，所以我们
our pl V's A's are PL these are the
primitive lattice vectors okay so we've
现在定义了直接晶格，然后我们将猜测我要制作一个
defined the direct lattice now and then
we're going to guess I'm going to make a
猜测这是一个很好的猜测，这是正确的猜测，我们将
guess of what this is a very good guess
it's correct guess and we're gonna have
为了证明这一点，请稍后猜测POV的PL v。
每个小伙子互惠的格子
reciprocal lattice every sip lad
我们将它们称为B sub I，并将其与直接晶格的sub I进行比较，我们将
we'll call them B sub I is compared to a
sub I for the direct lattice and we'll
通过以下等式b定义它们，sub j等于2 pi
define them by the following equation b
sub i gotted with a sub j equals 2 pi
Delta IJ这是一个非常重要的方程式
Delta IJ it's a rather important
equation now first thing you might
想知道如何直接给定一组原始晶格向量
wonder is how do I know given a set of
primitive lattice vectors in direct
我怎么知道有一组向量B满足这个
space a how do I know that there's a set
of vectors B which satisfies this this
对偶空间对偶向量空间基础的方程式排序
equation sort of a dual space dual
vector space basis well there's a fairly
向您展示可以通过一些帮助找到蜜蜂的简便方法，方法是编写
easy way to show you that you can find
bees given some aids which is by writing
他们写下来，让我们写下来，所以bi等于2
them down
so let's write them down so bi equals 2
pi aj cross ak over让我们看到一个1点缀成2个cross并3个
pi aj cross a k over let's see a 1
dotted into a 2 cross a 3 okay and this
对于ijk等于1 2 3或3 1 2或2 3 1，所以以循环方式，所以我主张
is for ijk equals to 1 2 3 or 3 1 2 or 2
3 1 so in the cyclical way so I claim
B的表达式将满足B的定义并对其进行检查
that this expression for B will satisfy
this definition of B and to check it
让我们来找出它是否正确，所以以B 1为例
let's uh let's just find out if it's
true so let's take for example B 1
点上1的点，这样写出来B 1 B 1是2 pi a 2跨过点1上的3
dotted with a 1 so well write out B 1 B
1 is 2 pi a 2 cross a 3 over a 1 dotted
用2交叉3，然后我们将其点到1
with a 2 cross a 3
and then we want to dot that into a 1
我们看到分子和分母实际上是相同的，所以我们
and we see that the numerator and the
denominator are actually identical so we
只能得到2 pi，因为我们应该这样做，但是如果我们将B 1点到2
just get 2 pi as we're supposed to
however if we took B 1 dotted into a 2
我们将得到相同的表达式，这里是一个2交叉，一个3向上，然后这个
we would get the same same expression
here a 2 cross a 3 up top and then this
楼下的整个表情我走的不对，然后点到一个2
whole expression downstairs I'm not
going right and then dotted into a 2 and
那东西等于0，因为当您怀疑它与2交叉时，它与3正交
that thing equals 0 because a 2 cross a
3 is orthogonal to a 2 when you doubt it
变成2，你得到0，所以B 1 +点a 1确实给你2 pi B 1 a 2给你
into a 2 you get 0 so indeed the B 1 +
dot a 1 gives you 2 pi B 1 a 2 gives you
0，您还可以检查它是否也适用于所有其他IJ组合
0 and you can check that it works for
all the other I J combinations as well
好吧，现在我们可以猜出倒数晶格矢量是什么
okay so now we have a guess for what our
reciprocal lattice vectors are so we
会猜测我们会将互易的晶格矢量G记为M 1 B 1
would guess that we would write down our
reciprocal lattice vectors G as M 1 B 1
再加上M 2 B 2再加上M 3 B 3好吧，现在将是我们的客人，但是如果
plus M 2 B 2 plus M 3 B 3 ok that's
going to be our guest right now but if
我们想证明这些G是互易的晶格矢量
we wanted to try to prove that these G's
are reciprocal lattice vectors are we
想要如果要证明晶格中的G，我们需要证明的是
want if you want to prove the G's in
lattice what we need to show is that the
如果我只想选择一个点，那么m只能是整数
m's can only be integers okay now if I
want to just pick any point in
倒数空间我可以选择用M的任意点将该点写为G
reciprocal space I can choose to write
that point as G with M's arbitrary so
让我以M的任意M开头，换言之，实数
let me start with M's arbitrary M this
arbitrary in other words real numbers
任意的，即允许考虑任何G考虑任何矢量任何矢量
arbitrary and that allows ie consider
any G consider any vector any vector
晶格，所以我将考虑从现在开始的任何可能的G，然后
lattice so I'm going to consider any
possible G to begin with now then what
我们要做的是强加定义eetu IG点R
we're going to do is we're going to
impose the definition eetu the I G dot R
等于1，所以我们将其强制为1等于IG点R e ok
equals 1 so we're going to force on it 1
equals e to the I G dot R ok what does
表示我对G的e是m1 v1加m2 B 2加M 3 B 3
that mean e to the I okay G is m1 v1
plus m2 B 2 plus M 3 B 3 in but run out
在1加n 2 a 2加n 3 a 3的房间N 1 a上确定
of room N 1 a
on a 1 plus n 2 a 2 plus n 3 a 3 ok and
如果我要将条件e施加到IG r等于1，我也需要这个
I need this too if I'm going to impose
the condition e to the IG r equals 1 I
必须使用我们的条件强加这个东西等于1的条件
have to impose the condition that this
thing equals 1 well using our
正交条件B点a bi AJ等于2 pi Delta IJ，即1等于e
orthogonality condition B dot a bi AJ
equals 2 pi Delta IJ that is 1 equals e
如果我想要2 pi IM 1 N 1加M 2和2加M 3和3
to the 2 pi I M 1 N 1 plus M 2 and 2
plus M 3 and 3 now if I want this thing
对于每个可能的n的每个可能的直接晶格矢量等于1
to equal 1 for every possible direct
lattice vector for every possible n the
只有这样，这才是正确的，这对于所有N的所有n都是正确的，并且仅当M为
only way this will be true this is true
for all n for all N and only if M are
整数EMAS是可以确定的整数，这意味着为了满足我们
integers EMAS are integers ok so that
means that in order to satisfy our
IGR等于1的倒数晶格的定义是
definition of the reciprocal lattice
that e to the IGR equals 1 for all are
在直接晶格中，唯一可行的方法是选择
in the direct lattice the only way we
can do that is if we choose G of that
MS整数的形式，因此G是晶格，我们不仅知道G
form with the MS integers therefore G is
a lattice and not only do we know that G
是一个晶格我们知道它的原始晶格矢量是什么
is a lattice we know what its primitive
lattice vectors are so we just derived
到目前为止，G是具有原始格向量的格
the fact that G is a lattice with those
primitive lattice vectors so far so good
我对那好事感到满意，但实际上我认为这两个有趣的事实
happy with that ok good a couple of
interesting facts fact actually I think
这是一个家庭作业的问题，也许是关于家庭作业的修订等等
this is a homework problem maybe on the
revision of homework or something then
我们简单地添加一下，我们坐在FCC的平面是BCC BCC，反之亦然
we simply add we sit flat of FCC is BCC
BCC and vice versa kind of an
有趣的陈述，您可以检查一下，我想您可能会选择其中一项
interesting statement you can check it
and I think you probably will for one of
您的家庭作业中另一个有趣的注释是它旨在将D变成D
your homeworks another interesting
comment is it's aimed that into D into D
适用相同的规则适用规则，但您可能想知道如何处理
same rules apply rules apply but you
might wonder how do you handle this
2D中的公式，因为我只有两个向量，而不是三个向量
formula in 2d because I only have two
vectors not three well the way you do
您处理公式只是选择a3等于Z hat
you handle that formula is just choose
choose a3 equals Z hat a point coming
离开飞机，换句话说，如果您生活在2D模式中，您会想象有一个
out of the plane so in other words if
you live in 2d you imagine there's a
垂直于平面，您将其视为第三个原始晶格因子，
normal to a plane and you treat that as
your third primitive lattice factor and
你从那里去，你生意很好，离我们还有几分钟
you go from there and you're in business
all right a couple of minutes left we're
在接下来的几堂课中我们将尝试做一些
going to try to in the next couple
lectures we're going to try to do some
对等格的解释和一些用途
interpretation and some uses of this
reciprocal lattice there's a rather
人们经常做出互惠格子的重要声明
important statement that people
frequently made the reciprocal lattice
是直接直接的傅立叶变换
is the Fourier transform Fourier
transform transform of direct direct
这也许不足为奇，因为倒易晶格存在于k空间中
this maybe isn't surprising because the
reciprocal lattice lives in k-space
而直接的格子生活在现实中是隔开的，你知道从我们这里得到
and the direct lattice lives in real are
spaced and you know to get from our
空间到K空间，您经常需要执行傅立叶变换等操作，但是
space to K space you frequently have to
do things like Fourier transform but let
我看看是否可以使此操作更加严格，让我们在1d中再次进行操作
me see if we can make this a little bit
more rigorous let's do it in 1d again so
我们的晶格向量是N等于N乘以N，我们如何去傅立叶
our lattice vectors are N equals a times
N and how are we going to Fourier
很好地变换那个格子，让我们做一个X的函数Rho
transform that lattice well let's make a
function Rho of X which is a sum over
三角函数的所有晶格点在每个晶格点的位置
all lattice points of a delta function
at the position of each lattice point
好的，这就是所谓的增量函数
okay
this is what's known as a delta function
梳子Delta函数梳子您在量子力学中是否曾见过
comb Delta function comb have you seen
this before in some in quantum mechanics
或类似的梳子，看起来像是X轴，然后
or something comb okay it looks kind of
like this here's the x-axis and then
这是0这是2 a 3 a，它具有这些很大的Delta函数峰值
here's 0 here's a here's 2 a 3 a and it
has these great big Delta function peaks
在每个晶格点的位置上，可以尝试傅立叶
at the position of each of these lattice
points ok that's try Fourier
对其进行变换，以使X的Rho的傅立叶变换等于DX e到ikx
transforming it so Fourier transform of
Rho of X equals integral DX e to the ikx
然后我们有这个Rho X功能并插入X Rho功能
then we have this Rho of X function and
plug in the Rho of X function we'll pull
求和，这样就得到了N个积分DX e的和，即I KX和Delta
out the sum so we get sum over N
integral DX e to the I KX and Delta
X减去RN的函数，我们让Delta函数起作用，所以我们
function of X minus RN
and we let the Delta function act so we
对I k RN求和，我们也可以写为ne的求和
get some over n e to the I k RN which we
could also write as sum over n e to the
我Kaena好的，这是什么，我们有这个
I
Kaena okay so what is this we have this
X的Rho的傅立叶变换，是所有这些阶段e至
Fourier transform of Rho of X and it's a
sum over all of these these phases e to
如果K是GM倒数晶格的元素，则IKr n好，则每个项
the IKr n well if K is an element of the
reciprocal lattice of GM then every term
这是IG n RN GM RN的e形式，因此每个项都是一个，因此
here is of the form e to the IG n RN G M
RN and so every term is one so this then
变成超过1的N的总和，如果有无限
becomes sum over N of the number 1 which
is infinite if you have an infinitely
大系统如果K不是倒数晶格的元素，那么我们拥有
big system if K is not an element of the
reciprocal lattice then what we have
那么我们所拥有的就是您会遇到一个复杂的阶段
then what we have is you'll have a
situation where this complex phase here
不等于1，所以它有一些复数相和任意复数相，
is not equal to 1 so it has some complex
phase some arbitrary complex phase and
那么，如果您到达的格子点是两倍大的double n，您将
then if you go out to a lattice point
which is twice as big double n you'll
得到两倍的复杂阶段，而您得到的结果却是原来的三倍
get twice the complex phase and you go
out to something as three times as big
您将获得复杂阶段的三倍，并且这些复杂阶段不断旋转
you'll get three times the complex phase
and these complex phases keep rotating
周围和周围，所以您会遇到一些振荡阶段
around and around and around so you get
some over oscillating phases which goes
归零，它们全部抵消，您得到零，所以最终可能是
to zero they all cancel out and you get
zero so at the end of the day it may be
我将移至此处，这就是它的傅立叶变换
I'll move over to here what we have
is it the Fourier transform of this
增量函数梳是所有可能的倒易晶格矢量K的总和
Delta function comb is a sum over all
possible reciprocal lattice vectors K
峰的负gm在倒数位置处的无限大峰
minus g-m of a peak an infinitely big
peak at the position of the reciprocal
晶格矢量，如果您仔细进行操作，则可获得2 pi的因数
lattice vector and if you do it
carefully you get a factor of 2 pi over
一个在外面a是这两个PI在a上的最后一个因素是相同的两个
a out out front a being the last factor
this two PI over a is it's the same two
当您进行傅立叶变换时显示的pi总是有两个PI
pi that shows up whenever you do Fourier
transforms there's always two PI's
漂浮在周围，所以他们总是在那里，你可能不会被抓住
floating around so they're always there
you're not probably going to be held
我怀疑有责任获得正确的前置因子，所以
responsible for ever getting this
prefactor right I suspect so the
原理是，如果您在真实空间中拥有增量函数梳，
principle is that if we have a delta
function comb in real space if you
通过傅立叶变换，如果您坐在一个
Fourier transform that the result is
infinite if you're sitting on a
倒数晶格位，如果您的K是倒数晶格矢量且它是0
reciprocal lattice site if your K is a
reciprocal lattice vector and it's 0
否则，这将成为增量函数梳
otherwise
and that becomes a delta function comb
在k空间中，现在相同的事物或多或少都存在
in k space ok
now the same thing more or less holds in
三维在3d中执行此操作，因此在3d中的3d中，我们将X向量的Rho等于
three dimensions do this in 3d so in 3d
in 3d we'll write Rho of X vector equals
如果您进行傅立叶运算，则将三角函数X的晶格点R的总和再减去R
sum over lattice points R of a delta
function X minus R again if you Fourier
转换它，您将获得X Rho的转换，您可以使用Delta函数
transform it you'll get for a transform
of Rho of X you let the Delta function
起作用并播种一个三维Delta函数Delta 3，这成为求和
act and sow a three dimensional Delta
function Delta 3 this becomes sum over
e到IK点R的晶格矢量R
lattice vectors R of e to the I K dot R
and then this thing becomes exactly the
以同样的方式，如果K是倒数晶格矢量，它是一个
same way that if K is a reciprocal
lattice vector it's the sum over an
无限数量的晶格矢量是发散的数字1，您将获得
infinite number of lattice vectors are
the number 1 which diverges and you get
无穷大，如果K不是倒数晶格矢量，那么您就不会得到
infinity if K is not a reciprocal
lattice vector then you don't get the
数字1会得到一些复杂的相位，而这个复杂的相位会旋转并
number 1 you get some complex phase and
that complex phase rotates around and
我们将它们相加并得到0，所以最终得到2个PI立方体
around and around and we add them up and
get 0 so you end up getting 2 PI cubed
超过晶胞的体积，沸腾的晶胞又可能
over the volume of the unit cell the
boiling unit cell again you're probably
不负责任的因素
not going to be held responsible for the
prefactor
k个倒数晶格向量G的倒数晶格向量之和
sum over reciprocal lattice vectors
of k- reciprocal lattice vector G okay
到目前为止，到目前为止，我们可以做得更好，甚至可以考虑
so far so good now we can do a little
better even we can consider things that
比起增量函数梳还要复杂，因为我们非常
are more complicated than just a delta
function comb because we're very
经常，我们实际上很少
frequently
we're very infrequently actually
呈现了真正的增量函数调用，因此我们将考虑
presented with a real delta function
call so instead we're going to consider
X的任何周期函数和X的周期函数角色，我的意思是
any periodic function a periodic
function role of X and what I mean by
周期函数是X的Rho应等于X加R的Rho，其中R为
periodic function is that Rho of X
should equal Rho of X plus R where R is
向后平移一个晶格矢量，因此X的此函数Rho等于
a lattice vector lat
back so this function Rho of X equals
X加上R的Rho，其中R是晶格矢量，它的周期为
Rho of X plus R where R is a lattice
vector it has the periodicity of the
点阵好吧，这样做有意义吗，好吧，好吧，现在让我们来研究傅立叶
lattice okay does that make sense yeah
okay okay so now let's take the Fourier
在X的Rho变换等于整数之前，此函数的变换
transform of this function before I
transform of Rho of X equals integral
d3x e到IK点X，这是X的所有空间Rho的积分
d3x e to the I K dot X and this is the
integral over all space Rho of X now
我们将做一些技巧，这将是一个有用的技巧
we're going to do a little bit of a
trick this is a useful trick that will
可能在某个时候回来困扰你，我将把这个积分
probably come back to haunt you at some
point I'm gonna take that integral over
所有空间，我将其写为所有晶格矢量的整数
all space and I'm gonna write it as an
integral over all lattice vectors are
那么单位晶格上的积分d 3x可能是较大的单位晶格
then the integral d 3x over the unit
cell maybe the bigger sites unit cell
周围都是周围，所以我只是在整个空间中分解该积分
around are around are so I'm just
breaking up that integral over all space
分为两部分，每个部分都在该位置周围的手指位点细胞上方
in two pieces each piece being over the
finger site cell around the position are
您的IK点X X的Rho，那么我们将定义一个参数Y x
you the I K dot X Rho of X then what
we'll do is we'll define a parameter Y x
等于R加y，我们将把那个积分重写为整数
equals R plus y like that and we'll
rewrite that integral then as integral
在单位单元的积分d 3y上求和
oops some over our sum over our integral
d 3y of over the unit cell
e到IK点的数量，我猜是R加y，然后是R加y的Rho，现在是R加y的Rho
of e to the I K dot I guess R plus y and
then Rho of R plus y now Rho of R plus y
Rho是周期的，因此R加y的Rho与Y的Rho相同，因此
Rho is periodic so Rho of R plus y is
the same as Rho of Y so that makes that
容易，然后我可以从此处将e分解为IKr项，我得到
easy and then I can factor out the e to
the IKr term from this here and I get
将R e加到括号中的IK点R的乘积
sum over R e to the I K dot R put that
in parentheses times this in parentheses
现在，将这些元素在e的单位单元上的d 3y积分到y的rh的I点y。
integral d 3y over the unit cell of e to
the I okay dot y of rho of y now these
第一个术语应该看起来很熟悉，因为我们刚才已经进行了计算
this first term should look familiar
since we just calculated a moment ago
这个东西是e到IKr的所有晶格向量的总和
this thing here is the sum over all
lattice vectors of e to the IKr
如果K为倒数晶格矢量，则为无限大，如果K不是倒数
if K is a reciprocal lattice vector this
is infinite if K is not a reciprocal
晶格向量，这个东西是0，所以这个东西就像我们在2 PI之前一样
lattice vector this thing is 0 so this
thing is just as we had before it's 2 PI
在所有倒易晶格向量上的单位像元总和的体积上求立方
cubed over the volume of the unit cell
sum over all reciprocal lattice vectors
我们的K减去G的Delta的G，所以它会给您一个在
G of Delta of our of K minus G so it
gives you a delta function peak at the
每个倒易晶格矢量的位置，在此被称为
position of each reciprocal lattice
vector this term here is known as the
K的结构因子s
structure factor s of K structure factor
结构因子，它只是我们所要函数的傅立叶变换
structure factor and it's just the
Fourier transform of the function we're
考虑在单个晶胞内，所以这实际上是一个相当有趣的
considering within a single unit cell so
this is actually a rather interesting
声明和相当重要的声明，我们将在以后使用很多次
statement and rather important statement
we're going to use many times later on
您可以采用任何周期函数，只要您进行傅立叶变换就可以了
you take any periodic function
whatsoever you Fourier transform it it
在倒易晶格的位置将只有大约非零值
will only have about nonzero values at
the position of reciprocal lattice
向量及其在那些值上的保留典型格向量的权重为
vectors and its value at those preserves
typical lattice vectors is weighted by
在单个单位单元内对函数进行傅立叶变换
the Fourier transform of the function
within a single unit cell there's going
在接下来的两三堂课中非常重要，所以我会见到你
to be extremely important in the next
two or three lectures so I will see you
在星期一，星期一，我想，我想，我会见你
on Monday Monday
I think Monday I think I'll see you
星期一好吧，周末愉快
Monday all right have a good weekend
you